Ali Rifaau Mohamed

UX/UI Designer

Experienced hospitality professional and emerging UI designer with a passion for creating seamless user experiences, bringing a fresh perspective and a blend of customer-centricity, problem-solving, and creative skills to enhance digital interactions and drive business growth.

ali.rifaau.mohamed@gmail.com

in /ali-rifaau-mohamed

\(+49 176 473 05195

Frankfurt, DE

https://rippe20.github.io/ Portfolio_site_rifaau/

UX/UI Projects

UX/UI Designer

Oct 2022 - Jul 2023

Dealz | App showing the best deals and discounts in proximity.

- Applied a user-centered design process and mobile-first approach to design a responsive web app for finding Deals and discounts in the proximity.
- Conducted competitive analyses, user interviews, surveys, and A/B testing to gather invaluable research data and develop personas and user flows.
- Designed low to high-fidelity screens Using Figma, Illustrator & Photoshop, resulting in a satisfying and intuitive userinterface.

Work Experience

Self employed

Mar 2020 - Present

E-commence, Graphic design, Promotions

Duty Manager

Mar 2017 - March 2020

Le Soleil d'Or, Cayman Brac, Cayman Islands

- Created standard operating Procedures (SOP) for the front office resulting the smooth day to day operations.
- Handled guest complains and short comings and improved the trip advisor and other online reviews about the hotel.

Front Office Supervisor

Aug 2015 - Feb 2017

LUX* South Ari Atoll, Maldives

- Trained new team members and conducted weekly training sessions for the team
- Supervised the reception & bell team and coordinated arrivals and departures.

Relevant Skills

- User Research
- User Personas
- · User Flows
- Prototyping
- Wireframes
- Branding / Logo Design
- · Style Guides
- Web Design
- · Basics in HTML,CSS &JavaScript

Tools

- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- · Usability Hub

Soft skills

- · Problem-solving
- Prioritization
- Persuading
- Time management
- · Attention to detail

Education & Learning

UX/UI Design Certification

CareerFoundry | Berlin | June 2023

400+ hours of UX/UI Design study and implementation, resulting in the end-to-end design of 4 applications and learned the basics of front-end development.